3cd9
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Pacific Crest Trail 2015</title>
	<atom:link href="/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Thru-Hike Attempt by Rick and Erica</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 21:58:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.7.3</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Registrations and logins disabled, site moving to static content</title>
		<link>/j/registrations-disabled/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 23:39:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rick AKA Apollo]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1340</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Due to spam and hack attempts, new user registrations and all logins for this website are disabled. edit 3/14/2017: I have disabled all comments for the same reason. edit 5/11/2017: due to continued hack attempts, I am taking this dynamically generated WordPress installation offline. I will migrate all pages to static content and keep the public-facing website online.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Due to spam and hack attempts, new user registrations and all logins for this website are disabled.</p>
<p>edit 3/14/2017: I have disabled all comments for the same reason.</p>
<p>edit 5/11/2017: due to continued hack attempts, I am taking this dynamically generated WordPress installation offline. I will migrate all pages to static content and keep the public-facing website online.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>July 9-11: The end of our 2015 season</title>
		<link>/j/july-9-11-the-end-of-our-2015-season/</link>
		<comments>/j/july-9-11-the-end-of-our-2015-season/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2015 17:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Starbuck AKA Erica]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://pct.frakkinhikers.com/?p=1280</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[More than one month after leaving the Pacific Crest Trail, we&#8217;re sitting down to recount our last few days in the backcountry during the 2015 season. &#8212; July 8 (continued) Start location: Bishop Pass Trailhead End location: ~1-2 miles west of Bishop Pass, on the Bishop Pass Trail Miles hiked: 6-7 miles (on the Bishop Pass Trail) &#160; Our last entry left off with [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>More than one month after leaving the Pacific Crest Trail, we&#8217;re sitting down to recount our last few days in the backcountry during the 2015 season.</p>
<p>&#8212;</p>
<p>July 8 (continued)</p>
<p>Start location: Bishop Pass Trailhead</p>
<p>End location: ~1-2 miles west of Bishop Pass, on the Bishop Pass Trail</p>
<p>Miles hiked: 6-7 miles (on the Bishop Pass Trail)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Our last entry left off with us in the lobby of the Creekside Inn of Bishop, catching up on our blog posts and preparing to do other chores around town before returning to the Bishop Pass Trailhead. After we finished our errands, we started hitchhiking in front of the post office, where it took us about 30 minutes to get a ride. Our driver was a local criminal defense lawyer in a beat-up old car that had plastic wrap and tape in place of a rear windshield. One of our most talkative rides to date, he told us all about his trouble recovering from drug addiction, his children from his previous marriage and from his current girlfriend, and about the town of Bishop in general.</p>
<p>As the three of us headed up into the mountains, the temperature dropped and the rain lashed down, making Erica (in the backseat) wish that we&#8217;d been picked up by someone with a more intact car. Fortunately, the weather was not as bad when we arrived at the trailhead, so we gathered up our things, thanked our driver, and headed back up the trail toward Bishop Pass.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Although it was late afternoon by the time we started walking, we wanted to summit Bishop Pass and drop down in elevation before setting up camp for the night. Other than occasional bursts of rain, the hike up to the pass was unremarkable and we didn&#8217;t bother taking many pictures. Once we reached the pass, however, the weather worsened. We found ourselves directly under a menacing cloud that pelted us with sheets of hail as we hiked down the west side of the pass. The hail followed us until we had descended ~1000 feet below the pass, where we got a long enough reprieve to make camp in a boulder field on the side of the trail. The evening air was cold, cold, cold, and we spent the rest of the night in our sleeping bags in the tent, hoping for better weather the following morning.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&#8212;</p>
<p>July 9th</p>
<p>Start location: ~6-7 miles west of the Bishop Pass Trailhead, on the Bishop Pass Trail</p>
<p>End location: Roughly the same as the start location</p>
<p>Miles hiked: ~4-5 miles</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>After going to bed in threatening weather the previous night, we woke up beneath the same cold, dark clouds. Because of the finger-numbing temperatures, we hurried through breakfast and breaking camp in the hope that hiking would warm us up. As we headed downhill toward the intersection of the Bishop Pass Trail and the Pacific Crest Trail, it started snowing&#8211;at first lightly and then heavily. The weather was definitely not going to be on our side this day.</p>
<p>Fewer than two miles before intersecting the Pacific Crest Trail, Erica, hustling too quickly for the sake of keeping warm, turned her left ankle on a rock&#8211;turned it hard. The pain was immediate and intense and given her history of left ankle sprains, it was clear that she wouldn&#8217;t be getting back on the PCT that day, if at all.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>After taking a big dose of ibuprofen and wrapping the ankle in a compression bandage, we decided that the best option was to backtrack over the Bishop Pass Trail rather than moving forward. Continuing on to the PCT would have meant several days of hiking to our next resupply point at the Vermillion Valley Resort, and with Erica&#8217;s ankle already swollen and difficult to walk on, that seemed like a poor choice compared to the ~8-mile hike back to the Bishop Pass trailhead. And so, disheartened and still cold, we started back up the way we had come.</p>
<p>It was not long, however, before the snow became too heavy to walk through. With Erica&#8217;s ankle severely compromised and Rick having to carry her pack, we did something we had never done before: We set up our tent in the middle of the day to wait out the weather. Fortunately, we found a nearby stealth camping site in a small grove of pine trees that afforded us some shelter as we hastily set up the tent. We both crawled into Rick&#8217;s sleeping bag for warmth and dozed off while the snow continued to fall outside.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Finally, after an hour or two, the snow stopped and we emerged from our tent to find that two section hikers on their way down to the PCT had chosen some rocks nearby on which to take their own break. The sun had started to come out by that time and the rocks were warmer than our tent site, so we moved ourselves and our things over there to dry.</p>
<p>As we sat on the rocks having lunch and talking to the section hikers, a man on horseback leading a group of at least six supply horses passed by on his way to the PCT. Had he been going the other way, up to Bishop Pass, we might have asked him for a ride, but he explained that he was delivering supplies to a trail crew working somewhere in the valley. Once the horses passed, we packed up our things and continued east on the Bishop Pass Trail, with Rick still carrying Erica&#8217;s pack.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Our progress was slow for the rest of the afternoon&#8211;not surprising, given Erica&#8217;s ankle&#8211;but we did somehow manage to outpace a foursome of section hikers on our way uphill. By early evening we found ourselves a nice campsite not far from where we had slept the previous night, meaning that we had more or less hiked in a circle. Disheartening for sure, but it could have been worse; At least we were self-evacuating and not waiting on a helicopter ride back to town&#8230;</p>
<p>The weather this night was even colder than the last. We ate dinner in the tent, bundled in our sleeping bags, preferring the chance of a bear encounter over the certainty of freezing our fingers off outside. It got so cold that we woke in the middle of the night to a frost-crusted tent; Dew from outside and condensation from within had frozen solid to create a thin, sparkling shell all around us&#8211;an oddly pretty sight that we had never seen before. We went back to sleep hoping for a sunny morning.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&#8212;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>July 10</p><p>
        <ins class="adsbygoogle"
	     id="ggad1"
             data-ad-client="ca-pub-2595593351458602"
             data-ad-slot="8770774774"
             data-ad-format="horizontal"></ins>
        </p>
<p>Start location: ~2 miles west of Bishop Pass, on the Bishop Pass Trail</p>
<p>End location: Motel 6 in Mammoth Lakes, by way of Bishop</p>
<p>Miles hiked: ~7 miles on the Bishop Pass Trail</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>We woke to the first bit of sunshine and blue sky that we had seen since leaving Bishop. It didn&#8217;t last long, but it was enough to thaw our tent and other gear before we packed up and hit the trail.</p>
<p>Thanks to the compression wrap and loads of ibuprofen, Erica&#8217;s ankle was less acutely painful than it was the previous day, although Rick still (valiantly) carried her pack to make the going easier. We made our way slowly up Bishop Pass and down the other side again, passing many day and section hikers in the process. We were also passed by the team of supply horses that we had seen the previous day. When we explained to the team&#8217;s leader that Erica had sprained her ankle, he offered to give us a ride down to the trailhead (still some 5 miles away), but we declined, remembering that neither of us is particularly good on horseback.</p>
<p>The rest of the hike was fairly unremarkable, except for the large number of other hikers we encountered on our way. The Bishop Pass Trail, while longer than most side trails that a thru-hiker would take into town, is very popular with section hikers. It possess the distinctive beauty you expect from the High Sierras, while still being easily accessible as a weekend trip. Lucky for us, the abundance of short-distance hikers meant that we did not have a hard time getting a ride back into Bishop. As soon as we got to the trailhead, we got a ride with a trio of car campers who had come to the area to fish. They were nice enough to drop us off at the McDonald&#8217;s in town so we could have something to eat while figuring out our next move.</p>
<p>After weighing our options, and considering that Erica would have to take another extended break from the trail, if not give up on it entirely, we decided to head to Mammoth Lakes to retrieve some packages from the post office there before making our way back home</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Our hitchhike up to Mammoth Lakes was from a middle-age woman employed by CalTrans as a sort of realtor. She was on her way home to Mammoth from Bishop (where she works) and took us to the Motel 6 in Mammoth, where we ended up staying the night. The Motel 6 was pricey and very crowded with a mixture of international tourists and hikers. Both Pacific Crest Trail and John Muir Trail hikers were represented, although we didn&#8217;t do much socializing. Getting off trail for an injury always elicits a certain amount of thinly veiled pity, which generally isn&#8217;t fun to be the subject of. So we kept to our room and talked about our options, agreeing that we would hitchhike to Irvine together the following day and then take things from there.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Little did we know that that would be our last day on the trail together for the season.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&#8212;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>July 11</p>
<p>Start location: Mammoth Lakes</p>
<p>End location: Irvine</p>
<p>Miles hiked: 0</p>
<p>Miles hitchhiked: Over 330 miles</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The trek back home was a long one, but we were lucky to find rides in a reasonable amount of time, making it from Mammoth Lakes back to Irvine (a ~330-mile drive) within 12 hours.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Our first ride&#8211;from a man on vacation with his family&#8211;took us from the main street of Mammoth to the closest 395 on-ramp, where we got our second ride from a pair of Europeans road-tripping the West Coast in a rental car. Our drivers, one German man and one Scandinavian man, were roughly our age or a few years older, very friendly, and very into techno music, which they blasted the whole way into town. They took us as far as Lone Pine, where the four of us had lunch together at a Carl&#8217;s Jr. (In their quest to find the best American fast food burger, they decided that Carl&#8217;s was definitely in the lead.)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Next, we got a ride from one end of Lone Pine to the other. This third hitchhike came from a young Belgian couple also road-tripping the West Coast, just like our last ride. The couple was our age and, unlike the our last ride, they had bought an old van once they got to the States and outfitted it with a mattress and camping gear. In a few days, the girlfriend would go back home while the boyfriend started hiking the John Muir Trail. It&#8217;s a pity we couldn&#8217;t ride with this couple longer; we probably would have had a good deal in common with them.</p>
<p>Once we got to the south side of Lone Pine, dropped off in front of a local gas/convenience store, we started our longest hitchhike wait of the day&#8211;of the whole hike, in fact. It took roughly three hours of sitting/standing on the roadside with our thumbs out, waving signs, hiding from the mid-afternoon desert sun before we finally got a ride. A few people stopped to talk to us in the meantime, including a pair of road-tripping girls from Georgia who offered us money (which we declined), but it wasn&#8217;t until after 5 pm that a station wagon pulled over to offer us our fourth ride of the day.</p>
<p>The driver was a software engineer working at Disney Studios and was on his way back to LA after a section hike in the Sierras. We rode with him all the way to Venice Beach, where one of Rick&#8217;s former co-workers had generously offered to drive us the rest of the way down to Irvine. Tired and stinky when we arrived in Venice Beach after 10 pm, we had a couple of drinks with Rick&#8217;s co-worker before embarking on the final leg of our journey. It wasn&#8217;t until after midnight that we finally crawled into bed, exhausted and thankful to be home</p>
<p>Thanks to everyone who gave us rides that day!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>

5a51
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/j/july-9-11-the-end-of-our-2015-season/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Photos: Kearsarge Pass to Bishop Pass</title>
		<link>/j/photos-kearsarge-pass-bishop-pass/</link>
		<comments>/j/photos-kearsarge-pass-bishop-pass/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 22:19:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rick AKA Apollo]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://pct.frakkinhikers.com/?p=1216</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<div class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="/j/photos-kearsarge-pass-bishop-pass/"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1248" width="150" height="150" src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6515-150x150.jpg" alt="Flowers on Bishop Pass" title="Flowers on Bishop Pass" /></a></div>Photos from our hike along the Pacific Crest Trail from Kearsarge Pass to Bishop Pass. Includes Rae Lakes, Mather Pass, and Pinchot Pass.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Photos from our hike along the Pacific Crest Trail from Kearsarge Pass to Bishop Pass. Includes Rae Lakes, Mather Pass, and Pinchot Pass. </p>
<div id="attachment_1218" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/?attachment_id=1218" rel="attachment wp-att-1218"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1218" src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6208-300x225.jpg" alt="Onion Valley Trailhead, leads up to Kearsarge Pass" width="300" height="225" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6208-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6208.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Onion Valley Trailhead, leads up to Kearsarge Pass</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1219" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/?attachment_id=1219" rel="attachment wp-att-1219"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1219" src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6211-300x225.jpg" alt="East side of Kearsarge Pass" width="300" height="225" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6211-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6211.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">East side of Kearsarge Pass</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1221" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/?attachment_id=1221" rel="attachment wp-att-1221"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1221" src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6215-300x225.jpg" alt="Top of Kearsarge Pass" width="300" height="225" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6215-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6215.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Top of Kearsarge Pass</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1222" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/?attachment_id=1222" rel="attachment wp-att-1222"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1222" src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6216-300x225.jpg" alt="Top of Kearsarge Pass" width="300" height="225" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6216-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6216.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Top of Kearsarge Pass</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1220" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/?attachment_id=1220" rel="attachment wp-att-1220"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1220" src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6214-300x225.jpg" alt="Top of Kearsarge Pass" width="300" height="225" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6214-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6214.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Top of Kearsarge Pass</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1223" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/?attachment_id=1223" rel="attachment wp-att-1223"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1223" src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6217-300x225.jpg" alt="Top of Kearsarge Pass" width="300" height="225" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6217-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6217.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Top of Kearsarge Pass</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1224" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/?attachment_id=1224" rel="attachment wp-att-1224"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1224" src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6218-300x225.jpg" alt="Another fat marmot" width="300" height="225" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6218-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6218.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Another fat marmot</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1225" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/?attachment_id=1225" rel="attachment wp-att-1225"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1225" src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6221-300x225.jpg" alt="View from campsite near Kearsarge Pass" width="300" height="225" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6221-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6221.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">View from campsite near Kearsarge Pass</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1226" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/?attachment_id=1226" rel="attachment wp-att-1226"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1226" src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6225-300x225.jpg" alt="Kearsarge Pass hailed-on campsite" width="300" height="225" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6225-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6225.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Kearsarge Pass hailed-on campsite</p></div>
<p><div id="attachment_1227" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/?attachment_id=1227" rel="attachment wp-att-1227"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1227" src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6231-300x225.jpg" alt="Hail near Kearsarge Pass" width="300" height="225" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6231-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6231.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Hail near Kearsarge Pass</p></div><div id="attachment_1231" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/?attachment_id=1231" rel="attachment wp-att-1231"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6277-300x225.jpg" alt="One of the many lakes in the area of Rae Lakes and the 60 lakes trail. On the descent from Mather Pass." width="300" height="225" class="size-medium wp-image-1231" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6277-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6277.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">One of the many lakes in the area of Rae Lakes and the 60 lakes trail. On the descent from Mather Pass.</p></div></p>
<div id="attachment_1228" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/?attachment_id=1228" rel="attachment wp-att-1228"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6255-300x225.jpg" alt="Pinchot Pass" width="300" height="225" class="size-medium wp-image-1228" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6255-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6255.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Pinchot Pass</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1229" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/?attachment_id=1229" rel="attachment wp-att-1229"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6259-300x225.jpg" alt="Pinchot Pass" width="300" height="225" class="size-medium wp-image-1229" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6259-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6259.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Pinchot Pass</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1235" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/?attachment_id=1235" rel="attachment wp-att-1235"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6290-300x225.jpg" alt="One of the many lakes in the area of Rae Lakes and the 60 lakes trail" width="300" height="225" class="size-medium wp-image-1235" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6290-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6290.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">One of the many lakes in the area of Rae Lakes and the 60 lakes trail</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1236" style="width: 235px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/?attachment_id=1236" rel="attachment wp-att-1236"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6318-225x300.jpg" alt="Mile 800 wooden suspension bridge" width="225" height="300" class="size-medium wp-image-1236" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6318-225x300.jpg 225w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6318-768x1024.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6318.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 225px) 100vw, 225px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Mile 800 wooden suspension bridge</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1245" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/?attachment_id=1245" rel="attachment wp-att-1245"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN63211-300x225.jpg" alt="Famous wobbly, wooden suspension bridge in the Sierras" width="300" height="225" class="size-medium wp-image-1245" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN63211-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN63211.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Famous wobbly, wooden suspension bridge in the Sierras</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1237" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/?attachment_id=1237" rel="attachment wp-att-1237"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6320-300x225.jpg" alt="Mile 800 wooden suspension bridge" width="300" height="225" class="size-medium wp-image-1237" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6320-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6320.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Mile 800 wooden suspension bridge</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1239" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/?attachment_id=1239" rel="attachment wp-att-1239"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6323-300x225.jpg" alt="800 Mile Marker, near the wooden suspension bridge" width="300" height="225" class="size-medium wp-image-1239" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6323-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6323.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">800 Mile Marker, near the wooden suspension bridge</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1241" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/?attachment_id=1241" rel="attachment wp-att-1241"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6394-300x225.jpg" alt="Deer near Sawmill Pass" width="300" height="225" class="size-medium wp-image-1241" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6394-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6394.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Deer near Sawmill Pass</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1242" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/?attachment_id=1242" rel="attachment wp-att-1242"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6402-300x225.jpg" alt="view from the ascent to Mather Pass" width="300" height="225" class="size-medium wp-image-1242" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6402-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6402.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">view from the ascent to Mather Pass</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1243" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/?attachment_id=1243" rel="attachment wp-att-1243"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6414-300x225.jpg" alt="View from Mather Pass" width="300" height="225" class="size-medium wp-image-1243" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6414-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6414.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">View from Mather Pass</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1247" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/?attachment_id=1247" rel="attachment wp-att-1247"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6490-300x225.jpg" alt="Metal bridge just before Bishop Pass. We ate lunch next to this." width="300" height="225" class="size-medium wp-image-1247" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6490-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6490-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6490.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Metal bridge just before Bishop Pass. We ate lunch next to this.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1240" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/?attachment_id=1240" rel="attachment wp-att-1240"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6378-300x225.jpg" alt="Taking a break at the top of Pinchot Pass" width="300" height="225" class="size-medium wp-image-1240" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6378-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6378.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Taking a break at the top of Pinchot Pass</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1248" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/?attachment_id=1248" rel="attachment wp-att-1248"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6515-300x225.jpg" alt="Flowers on Bishop Pass" width="300" height="225" class="size-medium wp-image-1248" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6515-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6515-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6515.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Flowers on Bishop Pass</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1250" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/?attachment_id=1250" rel="attachment wp-att-1250"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6524-300x225.jpg" alt="Automated snow sensor near Bishop Pass" width="300" height="225" class="size-medium wp-image-1250" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6524-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6524-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6524.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Automated snow sensor near Bishop Pass</p></div>
<p><a href="/?attachment_id=1253" rel="attachment wp-att-1253"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6416-300x225.jpg" alt="DSCN6416" width="300" height="225" class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-1253" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6416-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6416-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6416.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a></p>
<div id="attachment_1252" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/?attachment_id=1252" rel="attachment wp-att-1252"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6550-300x225.jpg" alt="Trail at water level on the east side of Bishop Pass" width="300" height="225" class="size-medium wp-image-1252" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6550-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6550-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6550.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Trail at water level on the east side of Bishop Pass</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1251" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/?attachment_id=1251" rel="attachment wp-att-1251"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6546-300x225.jpg" alt="east side of Bishop Pass" width="300" height="225" class="size-medium wp-image-1251" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6546-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6546-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6546.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">east side of Bishop Pass</p></div>
<p><a href="/j/photos-kearsarge-pass-to-bishop-pass/attachment/dscn6442/" rel="attachment wp-att-1254"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6442-300x225.jpg" alt="DSCN6442" width="300" height="225" class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-1254" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6442-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6442-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6442.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><br />
<div id="attachment_1254" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/j/photos-kearsarge-pass-to-bishop-pass/attachment/dscn6442/" rel="attachment wp-att-1254"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6442-300x225.jpg" alt="Mather Pass to Bishop Pass" width="300" height="225" class="size-medium wp-image-1254" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6442-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6442-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6442.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Mather Pass to Bishop Pass</p></div></p>
<div id="attachment_1253" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/?attachment_id=1253" rel="attachment wp-att-1253"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6416-300x225.jpg" alt="Mather Pass" width="300" height="225" class="size-medium wp-image-1253" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6416-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6416-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6416.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Mather Pass</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1252" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/?attachment_id=1252" rel="attachment wp-att-1252"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6550-300x225.jpg" alt="Trail at water level on the east side of Bishop Pass" width="300" height="225" class="size-medium wp-image-1252" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6550-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6550-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6550.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Trail at water level on the east side of Bishop Pass</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1251" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/?attachment_id=1251" rel="attachment wp-att-1251"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6546-300x225.jpg" alt="east side of Bishop Pass" width="300" height="225" class="size-medium wp-image-1251" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6546-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6546-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6546.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">east side of Bishop Pass</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1250" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="/?attachment_id=1250" rel="attachment wp-att-1250"><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6524-300x225.jpg" alt="Automated snow sensor near Bishop Pass" width="300" height="225" class="size-medium wp-image-1250" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6524-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6524-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/07/DSCN6524.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Automated snow sensor near Bishop Pass</p></div>

292f
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/j/photos-kearsarge-pass-bishop-pass/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>July 6-8: Relaxing at the Creekside Inn in Bishop</title>
		<link>/j/july-6-8-relaxing-at-the-creekside-inn-in-bishop/</link>
		<comments>/j/july-6-8-relaxing-at-the-creekside-inn-in-bishop/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 21:06:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Starbuck AKA Erica]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://pct.frakkinhikers.com/?p=1274</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We spent July 6-8 taking care of hiker errands and relaxing at the Creekside Inn, which is one of Bishop&#8217;s nicer hotel properties. Outside, the Creekside Inn has an actual creek running through the property, along with well-manicured green spaces, ample creek-side seating, and a nice pool and spa in a brick-lined courtyard. Inside, the rooms are exceptionally comfortable and [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We spent July 6-8 taking care of hiker errands and relaxing at the Creekside Inn, which is one of Bishop&#8217;s nicer hotel properties.</p>
<p>Outside, the Creekside Inn has an actual creek running through the property, along with well-manicured green spaces, ample creek-side seating, and a nice pool and spa in a brick-lined courtyard. Inside, the rooms are exceptionally comfortable and modern, decorated in woodsy brown colors. The lobby has lots of leather armchairs and couches, as well as large, framed photographs of the Sierras in various seasons. The lobby also has a large dining area where they serve hot breakfast daily (at no additional cost). In the evenings, the Inn sets out trays of fresh cookies; lemonade, iced tea and coffee are available throughout the day. In other words, it was a huge upgrade from the EconoLodge, although it came with a correspondingly higher price. Oh well. Sometimes the luxury is worth it.</p>
<p>Somehow, we racked up a big list of chores in the five days since we had last left Bishop: Rick had to replace his sleeping pad after one of the baffles failed (which has happened to him a few times in the last 1+ year of hiking). Erica had to order new shoes to replace the ripped up current pair. We needed to make changes to our upcoming maildrops. We needed to treat our clothes with permethrin in order to combat the onslaught of mosquitoes on the trail. And the list goes on&#8230;</p>
<p>Fortunately, staying at the Creekside Inn for two nights also gave us ample time to relax and hang out together. We ate several healthy, grocery store-bought meals on our patio overlooking the creek; we swam in the pool and soaked in the spa; and, of course, we stayed up late watching TV and enjoying the kinds of food and drink we can&#8217;t get on the trail. Suffice to say that many pounds of strawberries, vegetables, meats, and cheeses were consumed, along with several bottles of wine and local beer.</p>
<p>Now that we are checked out of our room, we are using the lobby computer to finish the last things on our chore list: updating this blog and backing up pictures. Soon, we&#8217;ll start hitchhiking back to the Bishop Pass trailhead, feeling well-fed and refreshed from another break in Bishop.</p>
<p>Our next stop will be at the Vermillion Valley Resort in roughly 4-5 days. We won&#8217;t have a hotel room there, but we will have showers, laundry and a resupply box to take us through the next stretch of trail. Unfortunately, it looks like we&#8217;ll continue having sporadic bad weather as we return to the trail, but that&#8217;s nothing new&#8230;</p><p>
        <ins class="adsbygoogle"
	     id="ggad1"
             data-ad-client="ca-pub-2595593351458602"
             data-ad-slot="8770774774"
             data-ad-format="horizontal"></ins>
        </p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/j/july-6-8-relaxing-at-the-creekside-inn-in-bishop/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>July 5th: Long Day back to Bishop</title>
		<link>/j/july-5th-long-day-back-to-bishop/</link>
		<comments>/j/july-5th-long-day-back-to-bishop/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 20:40:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Starbuck AKA Erica]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://pct.frakkinhikers.com/?p=1214</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We hiked nearly 20 miles, our longest day in quite a while. Only the first ~8 miles were on the Pacific Crest Trail, however; we spent the rest of the day on the Bishop Pass Trail, heading back into town. &#8212; July 5th Start location: Mile 823.2, 37.05463, -118.51474 End location: Bishop, CA via the Bishop Pass Trail at PCT [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We hiked nearly 20 miles, our longest day in quite a while. Only the first ~8 miles were on the Pacific Crest Trail, however; we spent the rest of the day on the Bishop Pass Trail, heading back into town.</p>
<p>&#8212;</p>
<p>July 5th</p>
<p>Start location: Mile 823.2, 37.05463, -118.51474</p>
<p>End location: Bishop, CA via the Bishop Pass Trail at PCT mile 831</p>
<p>Miles hiked: 7.8 on the Pacific Crest Trail, 11.8 on the Bishop Pass Trail (19.6 miles, total)</p>
<p>Miles hitchhiked: ~20 miles</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>We woke up around 7 am and found that our neighbors from the previous night were also just getting up. Within an hour though, they had packed up and hiked on, while we took an additional hour to get ready. We started walking after 9 am.</p>
<p>For the first two hours, we headed steadily downhill, following the creek that we had camped near the night before. We passed quite a few south-bound hikers on our way, but&#8211;as has become the norm lately&#8211;no other Pacific Crest Trail hikers. At this point, we are roughly 400 miles behind the rest of the pack, which is fine with us. Our intentions for this hike are different than other PCT hikers&#8217;, so it&#8217;s nice not to have to explain ourselves on a daily basis.</p>
<p>Other than a spectacular waterfall beneath the remnants of an old stone bridge, the hike down the valley was fairly unremarkable, and after a while, we found ourselves climbing back out of the valley along a different creek. The views uphill were of soaring peaks, inviting meadows, and dense trees. We saw a number of deer and a few other hikers, but it mostly felt like we had the trail to ourselves.</p>
<p>At around 12:15 pm, we reached a bridge over a creek near several campsites, just before the intersection of the Pacific Crest Trail with the Bishop Pass Trail. We knew that the Bishop Pass Trail was going to be a long, steep climb, so we decided to take an extended lunch break by the bridge. We feasted on hummus and tortillas, tuna, Doritos, and various other snacks as our sweat-soaked socks dried in the sun. Finally, at 1:30 pm, we packed up and headed toward the Bishop Pass Trail.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p><p>
        <ins class="adsbygoogle"
	     id="ggad1"
             data-ad-client="ca-pub-2595593351458602"
             data-ad-slot="8770774774"
             data-ad-format="horizontal"></ins>
        </p>
<p>The Bishop Pass Trail, at 11.8 miles long, is less frequently used by PCT hikers than the 7.5 mile-long Kearsage Pass Trail ~50 miles south of it. However, the trail does see a lot of foot traffic from section hikers and Rangers; we passed quite a few people on our way up to the pass.</p>
<p>Unlike all of the other passes we&#8217;ve tackled in the Sierras, the hardest part of the Bishop Pass Trail is right at the start. The first ~2 miles consist of steep switchbacks that parallel a waterfall, and the next stretch is a similarly steep grade. Roughly 2/3 of the way up to the pass, the trail levels out into a meadow-like environment that straddles the treeline. This area has a lot of tent sites and we saw several groups of section hikers camped out less than 2 miles before the pass. We stopped and talked to one such group while filtering water from a stream. The all-lady group was completing a 5-day, 60-mile hike from North Lake to South Lake and they were very interested in talking to a couple of PCT hikers. They even offered to give us a ride into town from the trailhead if we hadn&#8217;t found one before they got there. Section hikers can be pretty cool sometimes!</p>
<p>The last 2 miles up to Bishop Pass were less steep and had fewer switchbacks than the other passes we&#8217;ve tackled out here. At the top, the view was mostly obscured by the surrounding mountains, but we could see the alpine lakes down the trail to the east&#8211;very pretty. By then it was 5:30 pm and we had 5 more miles to hike down to the trailhead, which meant that if we hustled, we could make it back to Bishop that very night! (Earlier in the day, we had talked about camping on the Bishop Pass Trail and getting into town first thing the following morning.)</p>
<p>Propelled by a strong desire to eat pepperoni pizza, take long showers, and sleep in a real bed, we all but ran down the trail, which, like the Kearsage Pass Trail, was very scenic. About midway down the hill, however, a storm cloud blew over us and, despite the sun shining brightly in the west, started dropping hail and rain on our path. This was the third time in five days that we&#8217;d been caught in a sudden burst of bad weather, but we didn&#8217;t care; town was so close we could almost taste the pizza!</p>
<p>By 7:30 pm, we arrived at the Bishop Pass trailhead, just in time to accept a ride into town from a day hiker who was on his way into Bishop. The day hiker was an older guy driving a pickup whose truck bed he had converted into an actual bed (he had slept at the trailhead the night before). Rick sat up front with the driver while Erica flopped down with the packs in the back; it was more comfortable than it sounds.</p>
<p>We got into town at dusk and decided to go to the EconoLodge for the night because it was still the cheapest option in town (with breakfast). We indulged in the pepperoni pizza we had been dreaming of and, in our usual fashion, stayed up late watching TV and eating before finally falling asleep. A long day with a relaxing ending!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>

3008
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/j/july-5th-long-day-back-to-bishop/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>June 27-June 30: Time off in Bishop</title>
		<link>/j/june-27-june-30-time-off-in-bishop/</link>
		<comments>/j/june-27-june-30-time-off-in-bishop/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 19:52:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Starbuck AKA Erica]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://pct.frakkinhikers.com/?p=1210</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[After staying the night of the 26th in Independence, CA, we hitchhiked up to Bishop (~40 miles away) and spent June 27-30 recovering from the last week of hiking. &#160; &#8212;&#8211; Start: Independence Inn, Independence, CA Stop: Bishop, CA (first night at Bishop Village Motel, next nights at EconoLodge) Miles hiked: 0 Miles hitchhiked: ~40 &#160; Because we spent June [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After staying the night of the 26th in Independence, CA, we hitchhiked up to Bishop (~40 miles away) and spent June 27-30 recovering from the last week of hiking.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&#8212;&#8211;</p>
<p>Start: Independence Inn, Independence, CA</p>
<p>Stop: Bishop, CA (first night at Bishop Village Motel, next nights at EconoLodge)</p>
<p>Miles hiked: 0</p>
<p>Miles hitchhiked: ~40</p><p>
        <ins class="adsbygoogle"
	     id="ggad1"
             data-ad-client="ca-pub-2595593351458602"
             data-ad-slot="8770774774"
             data-ad-format="horizontal"></ins>
        </p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Because we spent June 27-30 off the trail in Bishop, we are going to give you a quick summary of our zero days, instead of a full narrative. Here are some of the highlights from our time in Bishop:</p>
<ul>
<li>Got a hitchhike from Independence to Bishop from an older lady and her teenage granddaughter. Both were very nice; they had lots of stories to tell about the Owens River Valley and its various attractions.</li>
<li>Spent our first afternoon in Bishop at the Black Sheep Coffee Roasters, enjoying discounted breakfast burritos and yummy smoothies and coffee.</li>
<li>Stayed at Bishop Village Motel our first night. The room was clean and comfortable enough, but very outdated (decor clearly from the 60s or 70s) and a bit overpriced.</li>
<li>Stayed the next three nights at the EconoLodge of Bishop, which was a little dirty (especially the carpets) and outdated (no flat screen TV!), but adequate for a couple of hikers looking for a cheap room. (They seem to be the cheapest motel in town that still offers breakfast and has a pool.)</li>
<li>Spent the better part of every day running the usual hiker errands (resupplying, fixing/cleaning gear, washing laundry, etc.).</li>
<li>Spent our evenings hanging out by the pool, eating strawberries with Cool Whip and other grocery store-bought treats, watching TV, etc.</li>
<li>Saw &#8220;Inside Out&#8221; at the local two-screen movie theater. Loved it!</li>
<li>Visited the local outfitters, particularly Wilson&#8217;s Eastside Sports, which has a larger selection than the other two outfitters in town.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, we spent more time in Bishop than we thought we would, but we needed it. The Sierras are tough in every way&#8211;mentally, emotionally, and physically. The quality of the trail is more akin to what we experienced on the Appalachian Trail (steep, rocky, tiring) than on the rest of the Pacific Crest Trail. In addition, we often have to take miles-long side trails off of the Pacific Crest Trail just to reach the nearest town, which is often not very near at all. The difficulty of getting off and on the trail contributes to the overall difficulty of the experience. When something goes wrong, you have to wait days to make it right.</p>
<p>Of course, the Sierras are also gorgeous, and so during our time off in town we agreed to slow down on this part of the hike and really take the time to enjoy our surroundings. We&#8217;re planning to hike an average of 12-15 miles per day, which may mean that we&#8217;ll end up spending most of the summer in the Sierras. We&#8217;ve also agreed to add a few extra town/resupply stops to our agenda. Our goal right now is to hike no more than 5-6 days at a time in between pit stops. Hopefully, these efforts will help us struggle less and enjoy more.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/j/june-27-june-30-time-off-in-bishop/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>June 26: Forester Pass to Kearsage Pass</title>
		<link>/j/june-26-forrester-pass-to-kearsage-pass/</link>
		<comments>/j/june-26-forrester-pass-to-kearsage-pass/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 19:18:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Starbuck AKA Erica]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://pct.frakkinhikers.com/?p=1211</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We finished the climb up Forester Pass in the morning and then descended alongside an alpine lake-fed creek. At the end of the descent, we climbed up toward Kearsage Pass and the Kearsage Pass Trail, our route out of the mountains and into town for another resupply. &#8230;.. Start: Below Forester Pass Stop: The Independence Inn in Independence, CA Miles [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We finished the climb up Forester Pass in the morning and then descended alongside an alpine lake-fed creek. At the end of the descent, we climbed up toward Kearsage Pass and the Kearsage Pass Trail, our route out of the mountains and into town for another resupply.</p>
<p>&#8230;..</p>
<p>Start: Below Forester Pass<br />
Stop: The Independence Inn in Independence, CA<br />
Miles hiked: 17 (7.5 of them on the Kearsage Pass Trail)</p>
<p>We woke late in the morning (7 am) to find another tent set up at a campsite close to ours. The hiker, whose name we didn&#8217;t catch, said that he came into camp in the middle of the night after having been stalked by a mountain lion for the last mile. It was incredible to us that a mountain lion would be up at such a high elevation (12,500 feet), but we had no reason to doubt the hiker&#8217;s story&#8230;</p>
<p>After the other hiker moved on, we continued packing up slowly, taking turns guarding our food and gear from the marmots. Marmots, we&#8217;ve learned, have very little fear of people. While Erica sat on a rock making coffee, a group of three marmots continually tried to approach her. She could have pet them, they were so close. Although cute for a while, constantly fending off chubby rodents does get old; we were glad to start hiking by 9 am.</p>
<p>Given how close we had camped to the pass, the climb up Forester went very quickly. As the highest point on the PCT, Forester Pass typically offers far-reaching views of the High Sierras. Unfortunately for us, that view was obscured by smoke from a forest fire. We had seen the smoke rolling in that morning just south of the pass, but we had hoped that the air would be clear north of the pass. No such luck. We and the other hikers we met on the pass were alarmed to see that the mountains north of us were also shrouded in smoke.</p>
<p>The descent from Forester passes multiple alpine creeks and lakes. One particularly clear lake had about five other hikers swimming in it/recovering from their swim. We did not join them; it was too cold!</p>
<p>About an hour after we passed the lake, Rick spotted a mountain lion on the trail at an elevation around 11,800 feet. The lion crossed the trail into some bushes that clearly had a wildlife use trail running through them. After that, we no longer doubted that the hiker we&#8217;d woken up next to that morning had been telling the truth about his own mountain lion encounter.</p>
<p>The trail paralleled a creek for the rest the descent from Forester Pass. There were a few crossings and many places to get water&#8211;how nice not to carry much water! We ate lunch at the bottom of the descent, near a crossing with the aforementioned creek. Many hikers, including some of the section hikers we&#8217;d passed earlier in the day, passed us as we ate lunch. Watching the section hikers go by, we realized that PCT hikers were no longer the most numerous people on the trail in this region. Indeed, few of the people we saw even realized that they were on the PCT; they were following overlapping trails like the John Muir Trail, the High Sierra Trail, and a loop trail which sounds like &#8220;Great Lakes Loop&#8221;.</p>
<p>After lunch, we started climbing up to Kearsarge Pass. After a couple miles of ascending on the PCT, we reached the Bullfrog Lake Trail, which leads up to Kearsage Pass and connects with another trail to the Onion Valley trailhead, from which you can reach Independence, CA.</p>
<p>We ate another meal on the shore of Bullfrog Lake before the start of the toughest part of the Kearsarge Pass ascent. Not yet above timberline, our lunch spot was shady and beautiful; It&#8217;s a pity that the PCT proper doesn&#8217;t visit Bullfrog Lake.  We had mac and cheese, going all out with extra powdered milk. We were walking again by 4:30 pm.</p><p>
        <ins class="adsbygoogle"
	     id="ggad1"
             data-ad-client="ca-pub-2595593351458602"
             data-ad-slot="8770774774"
             data-ad-format="horizontal"></ins>
        </p>
<p>The climb up to Kearsarge Pass from there was steep and exposed. Thankfully, the weather was fair (albeit still smokey from distant wildfires). We passed a hiker we&#8217;d met previously at Casa De Luna, an Australian named Richard. He was heading back to the PCT as we were climbing out.</p>
<p>The summit of Kearsage Pass was, like Forester Pass  earlier in the day, smokey. We mingled with some section hikers from UC Berkeley while there,then began a long descent towards the Onion Valley trailhead, nearly 2,500 feet below us and several miles to the east.</p>
<p>The descent was scenic. The eastern side of Kearsarge Pass is great, even if it&#8217;s not part of Kings Canyon National Park (but rather Inyo National Forest). We passed multiple alpine lakes, and eventually paralleled a creek. That creek, lacking the switchbacks which make the trail we were on human friendly, descended much more quickly than ourselves. In multiple places it formed cascades, if not waterfalls. Rushing water was the soundtrack for our descent. The largest cascade/waterfall is very near the bottom of the descent near the trailhead: It was a few hundred feet tall.</p>
<p>We arrived at the Onion Valley trailhead around 8 pm. It was quickly getting dark out. There were few people in the parking lot nearby despite many parked cars which, evidently, belonged to people section hiking in the Sierras. Not wanting to spend the night at the trailhead, we walked around the campground nearby to see if anyone might want to give us a ride. One of the first people we asked said yes after Erica helped him unload some groceries, and the two of them got to talking.</p>
<p>Around 8:30 pm, we got dropped off at a gas station in Independence, CA. There&#8217;s not much in Independence, and, unfortunately, the hotel which best caters to hikers was full for the night. We stayed at the &#8220;Independence Inn,&#8221; a fairly new hotel in town. The owner has only owned it for two years. Prior to that, it was a roach motel. He&#8217;s doing a lot of renovations and landscaping to the place. We enjoyed our stay there, except for the fact that our room had a lot of ants.</p>
<p>There are few services in Independence (two gas stations, a few hotels, and about 2 restaurants, both of which were closed). We ate dinner at a taco truck that&#8211;as locals later explained&#8211;is always in town. After $20 in tacos and another $10 in gas station junk food, we were finally full.</p>
<p>We stayed up fairly late drinking and watching TV. By midnight we were asleep.</p>
<p>(This post written on July 1st after returning to the PCT over Kearsarge Pass).</p>

2b76
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/j/june-26-forrester-pass-to-kearsage-pass/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>July 1st and 2nd: Return to the trail from Bishop</title>
		<link>/j/july-1st-and-2nd-return-to-the-trail-from-bishop/</link>
		<comments>/j/july-1st-and-2nd-return-to-the-trail-from-bishop/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 02:30:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rick AKA Apollo]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://pct.frakkinhikers.com/?p=1203</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We hitchhiked back to the Onion Valley Trailhead from Bishop. We climbed over Kearsarge Pass (again), then continued onward over Glen Pass to the base of Pinchot Pass. We reached trail mile #800. &#8212;&#8211; July 1st end location:  On the Kearsarge Pass trail (not the Bullfrog Lake Trail), overlooking Bullfrog Lake July 2nd end location: at the southern base of [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We hitchhiked back to the Onion Valley Trailhead from Bishop. We climbed over Kearsarge Pass (again), then continued onward over Glen Pass to the base of Pinchot Pass. We reached trail mile #800.</p>
<p>&#8212;&#8211;</p>
<p>July 1st end location:  On the Kearsarge Pass trail (not the Bullfrog Lake Trail), overlooking Bullfrog Lake</p>
<p>July 2nd end location: at the southern base of Pinchot Pass, right near a famous wooden suspension bridge. 36.87361, -118.43826</p>
<p>On the morning of July 1st, we took our time leaving the Bishop, CA Econolodge that we&#8217;d spent the prior three nights in. Once we checked out of our room around 11:30am, we left our packs in the lobby. The hotel was kind enough to watch our stuff while we ran a few last minute errands around town.</p>
<p>Sometime between 2pm and 3pm we were walking out of town. A passing hiker saw our cardboard sign that read &#8220;Independence&#8221; and informed us that someone was at the Bishop hostel right then giving rides to Independence. We detoured to the hostel, and found out the ride to Independence was full.</p>
<p>We walked another few blocks out of town, when that same ride to Independence pulled over and started waving to us. Apparently, the other people going to Independence had all flaked. The ride was ours! The driver and his wife live in Independence and visit Bishop for its grocery stores. They make a habit of giving rides to hikers. They were kind enough to drive us up to the Onion Valley Trailhead, about 20 minutes from Independence proper.</p>
<p>The climb over Kearsarge Pass was easier than we anticipated. Apparently, a few zero days of rest makes climbing easy. At the summit, other hikers were resting. We joined them and conversed for about 20 minutes.</p>
<p>We climbed down the western side of Kearsarge Pass and stayed on the Kearsarge Pass Trail. We did not take the bullfrog lake trail. We broke camp on a bluff overlooking Bullfrog lake.</p>
<p>That was a mistake. By 9pm ominous clouds had rolled in. By 9:30pm we were hearing thunder and seeing bright flashes of lightning. By 10pm we were getting rained on. The wind picked up and blew our tent over a few times (our tent is not freestanding, so high wind puts heavy load on the stakes). By midnight hail was falling, each piece he size of a gum ball or pebble. We feared it would rip our tent.</p><p>
        <ins class="adsbygoogle"
	     id="ggad1"
             data-ad-client="ca-pub-2595593351458602"
             data-ad-slot="8770774774"
             data-ad-format="horizontal"></ins>
        </p>
<p>We did not fall asleep that night until about 2am. The next morning, July 2n, we slept in until about 9am. We didn&#8217;t start moving on July 2nd until about 11am.</p>
<p>Our day on July 2nd was short. We climbed over Glen Pass fairly early in the day. Many JMT hikers were there with us; no PCT hikers to be found. Views from Glen Pass were great, as you  can see many alpine lakes. Glen Pass is about 11,960ft elevation.</p>
<p>We continued down Glen Pass towards Rae Lakes. We stopped briefly to build a culvert in the trail at a location where a seasonal spring was pouring onto the trail. Looking ahead, we saw that the water was following switchbacks down the trail for a good tenth of a mile. A little big of digging and moving a few heavy, heavy rocks moved the water over the edge of the trail (rather than down the trail).</p>
<p>We ate lunch in the rain at Rae Lakes a bit later. We saw another PCT hiker there. She&#8217;d been on Kearsarge Pass with us the day prior. She too was moving slow from the prior night&#8217;s terrible weather. As we left Rae Lakes, we spent a few minutes hiking on the wrong trail (the &#8220;60 lakes trail&#8221;). We caught our error sooner than later, and thankfully only wasted about 20 minutes.</p>
<p>From there, we descended to the base of Pinchot Pass. The descent was beautiful but otherwise unremarkable. This camp site, at about 8700ft, is the lowest elevation we&#8217;ve slept at on trail in quite some time.</p>
<p>To get to our campsite, we crossed a wooden suspension bridge that is somewhat well known. The bridge is right around trail mile #800. It wobbles to and fro as you walk on it. Signs warn that only one person at a time should use the bridge. Indeed, it sways so heavily that, if two people were to use it, one could easily imagine a sway-induced  fall to the water below.</p>
<p>We made camp here around 7:30pm. We both had time to shower and eat dinner. It&#8217;s 10pm now. Goodnight.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/j/july-1st-and-2nd-return-to-the-trail-from-bishop/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>July 4th: Lake Marjorie to 823.0</title>
		<link>/j/july-4th-lake-marjorie-to-823-0/</link>
		<comments>/j/july-4th-lake-marjorie-to-823-0/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 02:30:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rick AKA Apollo]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://pct.frakkinhikers.com/?p=1200</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[July 4th: We continued our intentional pattern of moving at a glacial pace through the Sierras. We woke at 7am, then spent 4 hours repairing punctures in our sleeping/air pads. We climbed over Mather Pass at 12000ft, then descended a path with many waterfalls to 9000ft. &#8212;&#8212; July 4th Start location: Lake Marjorie, mile 808.9, near 36.94509, -118.42865 (coordinates to [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>July 4th: We continued our intentional pattern of moving at a glacial pace through the Sierras. We woke at 7am, then spent 4 hours repairing punctures in our sleeping/air pads. We climbed over Mather Pass at 12000ft, then descended a path with many waterfalls to 9000ft.</p>
<p>&#8212;&#8212;</p>
<p>July 4th</p>
<p>Start location: Lake Marjorie, mile 808.9, near 36.94509, -118.42865 (coordinates to waypoint, not to actual site)</p>
<p>End location: Mile 823.2, 37.05463, -118.51474</p>
<p>Our morning started late at 7am and involved no hiking for the first four hours. The prior night&#8217;s stay near the wooden suspension bridge at the base of Pinchot Pass left many punctures in our sleeping pads that had to be repaired. Our morning was spent submerging our air pads in Lake Marjorie to find holes. By the time we were walking at 11am, we&#8217;d repaired 9 punctures between our two air pads.</p>
<p>Why all the holes in our sleeping pads? Pine needles. They&#8217;re sharp enough to pierce our tent floor and sleeping pads together. Don&#8217;t camp on or even near pine needles if you use an inflatable pad to sleep on.</p>
<p>From Lake Marjorie we descended to about 10000ft. We passed a ranger station and a trail fork for Taboose Pass, a rarely used route east to US-395. The descent was unremarkable and views were mostly obstructed by trees.</p>
<p>After a lunch of Rick&#8217;s homemade, dehydrated chili (nom nom) at around 1pm, we began a long, gradual climb up to Mather Pass. This climb was very easy in comparison to past climbs in the Sierras. We followed a creek upwards most of the way. We were above treeline by 11000ft, and the views at that point became very scenic.</p>
<p>At around 11400ft, the weather turned. We&#8217;d been hearing and seeing distant nastiness throughout the morning, but it took until this point for us to get wet. In typical Sierras fashion, it wasn&#8217;t rain which fell. Rather, small (about the size of a pencil&#8217;s eraser) pieces of hail were hitting us. They hurt! Rick was glad to have kept his hardshell rain jacket, an item which he&#8217;d previously considered sending home.</p>
<p>When the weather cleared a bit about 10 minutes later, we finished our climb over Mather Pass. The final sets of switchcbacks (the last 600ft or so of climbing) are harder than the rest of the ascent. The trail in this area is barren, rocky, above treeline, and steep. It can hurt to walk on such rocky, otherworldly trail.</p><p>
        <ins class="adsbygoogle"
	     id="ggad1"
             data-ad-client="ca-pub-2595593351458602"
             data-ad-slot="8770774774"
             data-ad-format="horizontal"></ins>
        </p>
<p>At the summit of Mather Pass we encountered another couple, roughly our age. They too were rushing over to avoid the nasty weather. They took a picture of us and us a picture of them, then, with a loud crash of thunder, everyone left the summit. We were only up there for about 10 minutes total.</p>
<p>Our descent was, like the ascent, rocky. We donned our hardshell jackets for fear of the weather. Indeed, by the time we were down to 11000ft, we were again getting hailed on.</p>
<p>Views on the north side of Mather Pass are amazing. Waterfalls and cascades are abundant. Glacially carved rock formations line the steep hillsides. We followed a large creek for most of the descent, and often the trail approached  waterfalls over which said creek ran.</p>
<p>We should have stopped at around mile 820.7 near elevation 10600ft. The trail in that area is snaking through a small plateau. Rivers, waterfalls, and cascades run through the area. There are many picture-perfect campsites. We were in the area around 6pm.</p>
<p>But we didn&#8217;t stop. In retrospect, this was a mistake. We continued another 2.5 miles of descent to our current site, at approximately 9050ft elevtion. It&#8217;s much less scenic, though still very close to water. We didn&#8217;t make camp until 7:30pm, which is late by our lazy-hiking-the-Sierras standards.</p>
<p>Around 8pm some through hikers joined or tent site. The three of them are a bit cliquish; they don&#8217;t talk when we try to initiate conversation. Maybe it&#8217;s because their day (today) was as long as our last two days: they came from before Pinchot Pass to get here. #notforus</p>
<p>Goodnight.</p>

ed5
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/j/july-4th-lake-marjorie-to-823-0/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>July 3rd: Mile 800 (Wooden Suspension Bridge) to Lake Marjorie</title>
		<link>/j/july-3rd-mile-800-wooden-suspension-bridge-to-lake-marjorie/</link>
		<comments>/j/july-3rd-mile-800-wooden-suspension-bridge-to-lake-marjorie/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 02:30:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rick AKA Apollo]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://pct.frakkinhikers.com/?p=1198</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[July 3rd: We woke from a terrible night&#8217;s sleep  at mile 800. We hiked a very short day to Lake Marjorie at mile 808.64. We climbed over Pinchot Pass (12000ft) in doing so. &#8212;&#8211; July 3rd: Start location: stealth site about 50m north of the wooden suspension bridge around mile 800 End location: Lake Marjorie, mile 808.64 We slept terribly [...]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>July 3rd: We woke from a terrible night&#8217;s sleep  at mile 800. We hiked a very short day to Lake Marjorie at mile 808.64. We climbed over Pinchot Pass (12000ft) in doing so.</p>
<p>&#8212;&#8211;</p>
<p>July 3rd:<br />
Start location: stealth site about 50m north of the wooden suspension bridge around mile 800<br />
End location: Lake Marjorie, mile 808.64</p>
<p>We slept terribly the preceding night. Rain and pine needles conspired to keep us awake. Pine needes!?! They punctured our sleeping pads. Repeatedly. Both of us were basically sleeping on the ground; a deflated sleeping pad offers no comfort whatsoever.</p>
<p>Our morning was groggy and slow. We didn&#8217;t start walking until 11am and, from that moment, we were climbing upwards to Pinchot Pass (12000+ft).</p>
<p>Very early on in the climb we heard a waterfall rushing near the trail. We bushwacked off trail just a bit and found it. The waterfall was actually a very tall cascade. Water, over the last few tens of thousands of years, had erodes a solid slab of rock into all sorts of interesting contortions. The volume of water rushing by us just feet away (yea, we got pretty close) was truly remarkable.</p>
<p>Around 2pm we saw a bear. Thankfully a large ravine separated it from us. The bear was walking along a rocky hillside, moving roughly parallel to the PCT. It looked like the bear from the California  state flag set in motion.</p><p>
        <ins class="adsbygoogle"
	     id="ggad1"
             data-ad-client="ca-pub-2595593351458602"
             data-ad-slot="8770774774"
             data-ad-format="horizontal"></ins>
        </p>
<p>We took lots of breaks throughout the day. Lots of breaks. We realized sometime today or the day prior that our food wouldn&#8217;t last until Vermillion Valey Resort as we&#8217;d hoped. As a workaround, we&#8217;re planning to exit the trail (again) via Bishop Pass and visit Bishop, CA again.</p>
<p>Our decision to add  resupply at Bishop Pass leaves us with 6 or 7 days of food to move 30 miles. We truly have the time to enjoy the Sierras.</p>
<p>We reached lake Marjorie around 6:30pm and stopped. We could&#8217;ve kept going. We didn&#8217;t want to. We washed our clothes and relaxed with the extra time. We did not patch our air pads because we didn&#8217;t yet realize the extent of the damage caused by the prior night&#8217;s pine needles.</p>
<p>(Written the night of July 4th)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/j/july-3rd-mile-800-wooden-suspension-bridge-to-lake-marjorie/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

0

